Finding Aid for Alphadelphia Association Records, 1844-1857
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Alphadelphia Association Records 1844-1857
Alphadelphia Association
3 microfilm rolls.
93838 mf 232c;233c;234c
Communitarian society located near Kalamazoo, Michigan. Constitution, census, membership records, reports of committees, labor records, financial accounts, minutes of directors, correspondence and miscellaneous papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group is on deposit from James Buckley and his heirs (donor no. 3391 ) and came to the library in 1958.
The Bentley Library is also the repository for the originals of this record group
The record group is open to research.
Alphadelphia was a communitarian society, located near Kalamazoo, Michigan, and established in 1843. The association founded on the principles set forth by French socialist Charles Fourier which combined a belief in the possibilities of scientific evolution and social progress and the sense that ridding the world of evil would inaugurate a "reign of Social Harmony" that would hasten, according to the members of such groups as Alphadelphia, the coming millennium or the thousand year reign of Christ on earth.
The constitution for Alphadelphia was drawn up in December 1843 by a small group of individuals from various Michigan counties. These same selected members for a site committee to search out a suitable location for their home. Some partially cultivated acreage in Kalamazoo County seemed ideal for their purposes. The land was cut across by the Kalamazoo River and close-by the anticipated completion of the Michigan Central Railroad tracks. Those who owned land on the site were encouraged to join the organization.
In the spring of 1844 a barracks for living quarters was built. There would also soon be a saw mill for the timber on the land, a blacksmith shop, and a printing office. From this latter office, the Alphadelphia members printed the Alphadelphia Tocsin and a journal, the Primitive Expounder.
Alphadelphia lasted but four years and really flourished only for one year until 1845. Some members left because of poor economic conditions and their sense that they could better themselves elsewhere. Internal dissensions also tore at the organization with charges of mismanagement and the shortage of cash to do business and to pay taxes. Alphadelphia ceased functioning, according to their records, in 1848.
The record group consists of organizing documents, correspondence, land and labor records, financial records, and membership records.
Subjects:
Cooperative societies--Michigan.; Cridland, Charles R.; Galesburg (Mich.); Kalamazoo County (Mich.); Keith, Harvey.; Noyes, James.; Schettlerly, Henry R.; Tubbs, Lyman.; Alphadelphia Association.
Contributors:
Denton, Samuel, 1803-1860.
- Organizing records
  - Report of site-selection committee, December 27, 1843 (Reel 1)
  - Constitution, original, typescript and fragments (Reel 1)
    (printed copies of the constitution will be found in Primitive Expounder)
  - Roll of original members, March 1844 and membership census, March 1845 (Reel 1)
  - Articles of agreement and deed to domain (Reel 1)
- Correspondence
  - December 1843-June 1844 (Reel 1)
  - July-December 1844 (Reel 1)
  - January-May 1845 (Reel 1)
  - June-December 1845 (Reel 1)
- Other records
  - Reports of the General Council, 1845 (second) and 1846 (third) (Reel 1)
  - Reports of committees, 1843-1844 (Reel 1)
  - Reports of Council of Arbitration, 1844-1846 (Reel 1)
  - Proposals for membership, 1844 and undated (Reel 1)
  - Agreements to leave (Reel 1)
  - Appraisals of property (Reel 1)
  - Supplementary agreements between members and Association on certain items of property (Reel 1)
  - Labor record books (with names and types of employment) (Reel 1)
  - Building of mansion (Reel 2)
  - Alphadelphia Tocsin, vol. 1, no. 1; Friday, December 6, 1844 (Reel 2)
  - Tocsin subscription lists and accounts (Reel 2)
  - Stock holdings (Reel 2)
  - Stock certificates, A-Z, 4 folders (Reel 2)
  - Orders (to pay) on the council (Reel 2)
  - Receipts, 1844-1846 and undated (Reel 2)
  - Treasurer's reports (Reel 2)
  - Bills allowed
    - 1844-1846 (Reel 2)
    - Undated (Reel 2)
  - Bills, 1844-1846 (Reel 3)
  - Miscellaneous accounts (Reel 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Reel 3)
  - Bound volumes
    - Record book, 1843-1844 (Reel 3)
    - Account book, July 23, 1844-May 2, 1848 (Reel 3)
    - Record of labor performed, 1844-1845 (Reel 3)
    - Ledger, 1844-1845 (Reel 3)
    - Day book, July 23, 1844-April 30, 1848 (Reel 3)
    - Stock book, 1844-1845 (Reel 3)